[Music]
hi my name is Mike and here's my
favorite tips to help you get the most
out of co-pilot when you're looking for
those quick Data Insights in business
Central analysis assist is just one of
many co-pilot capabilities and it's in
preview in 2024 release Wave 2 in this
wave we've listened to customer feedback
and we've made things more reliable more
powerful powerful and more flexible as
well um so let's dive into those tips
right away so here's my first tip start
by picking the right list it's actually
really important so if you're interested
in insides for example about your
customers you'd go to the customer
list here you can use the co-pilot
toolbar or the co-pilot menu to get help
from co-pilot let's start with an easy
question who are my top customers and
bonus tip here you can use control enter
to send that to co-pilot without even
having to lift your hand off the
keyboard Bo now we' put co-pilot to work
co-pilot is trying to come up with a
layout uh of this information which
helps answer my question and there you
can see it's already drafted an initial
layout now um it's okay if you or
co-pilot don't get things right on the
first go because co-pilot hangs around
here to help you reiterate on that
design let's try something
else group this by country show EU
countries only
now here I can reiterate with co-pilot I
can continue improving and adapting that
layout of my analysis Tab and you can
see how it's grouped um the uh Records
by country and region code now what's
most interesting of course is that uh
the country and region code are actually
not on my uh my customer list uh so what
happened here how did these hidden
Fields suddenly appear uh well when I
say hidden Fields what I mean of course
is the fields that are on that list page
but are currently hidden and you can
normally bring them in through
personalization let's just take a quick
look at that these are the fields it's
about eight Fields eight columns that I
have on the customer list and typically
to add more Fields I'd go to personalize
it bring up the add a field Tab and that
contains what 20 plus more really useful
fields that I can simply click to bring
onto the page like country region code
now uh what copilot did there was it
shortcut all of this process for me it
helped me out by saying look there's a
country region code field simply hidden
on that list page I'll bring it straight
into that analysis Tab and once it does
that you can actually use that field
also in other tabs that you go and
create manually on the customer list so
copilot can only help with fields that
are here directly shown inside the list
or fields that are shown in this pane on
the right but if you ask for insights
which don't cover these fields co-pilot
probably can't help you and that's
really why it's crucial to pick the
right list to start with think about
where is it most likely that I'll find
the insights that I'm looking for and
for the next tip make sure you review
and adjust what co-pilot has created
sometimes you're just looking for a
quick Insight but other times you're
working on a task where those insights
fuel critical business decisions that
you need to make make so it's important
that you actually take the time to
review and adjust what co-pilot has
drafted for you let me show you how much
easier we've made that now in wave two
so here I'm back in the same tab that
was created earlier and first thing I
want to do is go check my filters so I
can click and interact to see which
filters co-pilot has applied you can see
it's applied filters for these two
countries onto the country region code
um but I can also look at the different
columns here I can even make adjustments
as well say let's bring in some contacts
uh let's remove the uh the balance from
there and make some adjustments directly
in the tab itself I'll resize some
columns I'll also drag and reorder some
of those columns and make sure that you
know the right things are expanded and
collapsed um so that's how you can
easily explore what co-pilot has drafted
for you and make adjustments but what's
more interesting is that um those manual
adjustments are now added to the history
here in the prompt dialogue so here you
can see I've got my adjustments that I
just made to um that analysis Tab and I
can actually navigate back and forth to
see the different t tabs to see which
one is my preferred option my manual
changes are included here as well and
when I'm satisfied with what I see
that's when I can choose to Simply hit
keep it and now I can get back to this
next time as well so the next tip will
really help you improve how you prompt
and how you send messages to co-pilot
start by keeping it really simple keep
your messages very concise don't use
long paragraphs or multiple sentences
which ask for a lot of different things
try to keep it real short and and if
you're not sure what to ask for use the
prompt guides to help you let me show
you how that works here I've got the
prompt guides menu and this contains a
whole bunch of inspirational prompts
that you can use uh giving a hint about
what compil it can do for you here for
example did you know it could actually
freeze some columns to make it easier to
uh scroll around and see those key
Fields uh you can apply different ways
of sorting uh ascending or descending or
different ways of filtering that data
and adding structure like grouping like
um showing basic math like sums and
averages uh or also even Advanced things
like pivoting as well so use the prompt
guide to give you those little hints as
to what you can do and what you can ask
co-pilot to do in this case now don't
forget it's okay to be imprecise and
it's okay to use abbreviations or
alternate words for things uh and it's
definitely okay for you to uh use the
grammar and the language that you are
comfortable with um it does not have to
be Flawless co-pilot is designed to deal
with that and be able to work with how
you express
yourself and of course you can express
yourself in your own language in fact we
have tested and verified analysis assist
in 20 languages now so you can express
yourself as you see fit but don't panic
if you don't see your favorite language
on this list because you can still use
analysis assist with any other language
in business Central just keep in mind
that it may not perform as intended and
results May Vary depending on your input
and the context in which you've applied
it as well so if you're interested to
see the whole list of supported
languages for all of business Central's
co-pilot features I've dropped a link
just below this video where you can go
look up the entire table of information
there and now for my final and favorite
tip you can actually start analysis
directly from the chat pane in business
Central you can chat with co-pilot to
get answers to how to do things uh ask
about felds and how they work or find
records in business Central or using the
power of your own words and you do this
in the chat pane on the side of the
screen let's see how that works let's
bring up the co-pilot pan on the side
here and I'm going to ask a quick
question Show Low stock items by
category I'll send that to co-pilot and
um copilot just knows that certain
questions are best answered or best
expressed as an analysis tab so so it'll
detect that it's that kind of question
and actually lead you to the right
place and there we go co-pilot has
responded uh indicating that this
information can be found on the item
list and uh it's actually giv me a
simple way to Simply click and start
generating that uh analysis tab which
may contain my answer uh so it's also
taken me to the item list it's drafted
up that analysis has done all of that
for me uh in just one click in a few
words and here you can see I've got all
of these items and it's a great
opportunity to apply the same tips I
mentioned earlier you know make sure
that it's gone to the right list uh make
sure that the filters are correct if
this is an important decision you're
making based on this data and these
insights uh and make sure you can you
know reiterate on the design correct it
and manually adjust it if you need to to
get to the Perfect Design before hitting
keep it so that's how you can go from
chat all the way to analysis tabs and
just a few words and a click as well so
those were my favorite tips this is when
you stop watching this video and go try
them out yourself you can even try out
analysis assist on your own custom lists
too if you like this video like And
subscribe to our Channel you'll get a
lot more of these and thanks for
watching and I wish you a productive
workday